Vladimir Golubyev

Full-Stack Software Engineer

Phone: (858) 603-2530 - Email: me@vlad.ai - Website: www.vlad.ai - LinkedIn: vlad-at-work

Experienced, versatile engineer with 7+ years of professional full-stack experience and a passion for solving business problems. Versed in JavaScript, React.js, GraphQL, Vue.js, Node.js, Jest, Ruby and Ruby on Rails. Experienced in deployment as well as development: Heroku, AWS, Google Cloud. Familiar with flavors of SQL and MongoDB. At home in SCRUM environments, turning Figmas and Zeplins into reality, writing documentation and mentoring.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Kazoo HR

October 2020 - Present

Utilized JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js and Ruby on Rails to deliver a cutting-edge HR solution which focuses on bringing fun to the world of HR.

- · Working closely with product and engineering teams to turn Figma mockups into customer-facing applications
- Refactoring complex legacy Ruby on Rails and Node.js applications in favor of a unified Node.js and PostgreSQL app architecture
- Working with QA teams for seamless testing and production releases

Software Engineer

Power Digital Marketing

Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

Using JavaScript, React.js, Node.js and Ruby on Rails, worked alongside marketing professionals to turn both legacy Node.js and Ruby on Rails applications into Nova: a unified product aimed at businesses in need of all aspects of digital marketing.

- Worked on creating a cutting-edge B2B advertising PaaS
- Maintained and refactored legacy Node and Ruby on Rails applications
- Worked on combining new and old tech: PHP/Laravel, React.js, MySQL, Ruby on Rails and Node.js into a new, cohesive product

Software Engineer (contract)

Intuit, Inc

July 2018 - August 2019

Utilized a wide variety of proprietary and open-source technologies focused on JavaScript, React/Redux and GraphQL to deliver features for the novel TurboTax Live! platform.

- Designed and developed features for TurboTax Live! using JavaScript, React/Redux serving millions of end-users
- Created, developed and tested both front-end and back-end features used by thousands of tax professionals internally
- Integrated complex front-end infrastructure to work with AWS-driven services using traditional APIs as well as GraphQL
- Created a comprehensive, automated testing suite to achieve 95%+ code coverage for staging and production artifacts using
 Selenium, Istanbul and Jest
- Worked with non-technical teams to identify and resolve bugs across the entire stack with Splunk

Founder & Software Engineer

Executable Media

June 2016 - Present

Worked on a variety of projects spanning eCommerce, social marketing, product logistics and customer support.

- Created an ad-serving infrastructure with a focus on performance and high availability, handling millions of impressions using **Node.js**, **Nuxt.js**, **MongoDB** and a variety of third-party tools and APIs
- Employed optimization strategies to achieve 100%+ improvement in sales funnel conversions using Vue.js, Node.js/Express.js,
- Created and made profitable a number of eCommerce resources and products
- Worked with Stripe, PayPal and Shopify APIs to create a boutique, high-performance Point of Sale system for eCommerce campaigns

Software Engineer (contract)

Lightfoot Media

June 2015 - September 2017

Worked on creating an ad-serving framework as well as developed a boutique Email Service Provider framework in tandem with outsourced resources, overseeing JavaScript, PHP and Python development.

- Led an international team to refactor an Email Service Provider framework Successfully improved UI/UX, decoupled legacy back end systems and introduced a testing pipeline
- Introduced SCRUM, version control, CI/CD pipelines to existing project
- Reduced the number of customer-reported bugs by 50% in the first month

Software Engineer (contract)

MarketTrend

June 2013 - September 2015

Worked on creating an ad-serving framework as well as developed a boutique Email Service Provider framework in tandem with outsourced teammates overseeing **JavaScript** and **Python** development.

- Led an international team to refactor an Email Service Provider framework Successfully improved UI/UX, decoupled legacy back end systems and introduced a testing pipeline
- Introduced SCRUM, version control, CI/CD pipelines to existing project

PERSONAL PROJECTS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Co-Founder & Developer

Abella Eyewear @ abellaeyewear.com

January 2018 - March 2020

- Refined a product line of fashionable eyewear
- Developed internal order management tools with Shopify API integration
- Created a number of highly optimized sales funnels using React

Co-Founder & Developer

PerformAIR @ performair.shop

February 2019 - present

- Created a number of profitable landing pages using Vue.js
- Implemented a number of APIs per business requirements: Shopify, PayPal, Stripe, ipStack
- Helped manage Facebook and GoogleAds campaigns
- Responsible for cloud hosting and maintenance

EDUCATION

Assistant & Developer

Alliant International University

2017

Worked under the guidance of Dr. Aaron M. Wester, PhD authoring a Ruby language curriculum for Alliant International University

Coursework

University of Idaho

2008 - 2011

Chemistry

Attended leadership development courses